Previously, on Heated Rivalry...
Can I ask if you've ever
been with another guy?
It's really OK.
Let's be best friends.
You and her are not...
We're not.
You're playing on the same team
as Hollander this year, right?
I don't think
I can keep pretending
I don't like you anymore.
You know I love you.
I know you do.
But it's not the same
as it is with Jane.
You scared me.
I was gonna ask you, will you
come to my cottage this summer?
You know we can't do that.
I'm coming to the cottage.
And the most valuable
player is Scott Hunter.
Thank you.
Um...
A few weeks ago,
I achieved my lifelong dream.
Winning the Cup.
Those of you who've done that
know how it feels.
I don't even think I have
the words to describe it.
But something else
happened that night.
Something you may have noticed
got a lot more attention
than the Admirals
winning the Cup.
It's, uh, it's been
an interesting month.
In case you missed it somehow,
I came out as gay
in a ridiculously public way.
And I've always been
a private person.
I've never really shared
anything about my private life.
But from what I've seen
over the past few weeks,
it's... it's maybe
important that I do a bit.
Fans have been
sending me messages...
and a lot of young fans,
telling me how much it meant
to them for me to come out.
And look, I love hockey.
I'm so grateful that I get
to do this for a living.
But I also know what
it feels like to not fit in.
When I was a teenager, I...
I realized that
I may be that thing
that hockey players like
to throw around as an insult.
The kind of language
that I heard
on the ice and in
the locker room every day
was a constant reminder
that I was different.
Wh-when you have a secret
that you work as hard as I did
to protect, it's, um...
It's exhausting.
It's a nonstop effort.
And it's also really, really...
lonely.
Thankfully, I found the person
who changes everything.
And he gave me the confidence
and strength
and the need to be honest
about who I am.
Fear is a powerful thing.
But this year, I found the one
thing that is more powerful.
So I share this honor with
my teammates and my coaches.
But I also share it
with you, Kip.
You have made me better
in every conceivable way.
I love you.
Thank you!
Is this a Jeep?
No, it's British.
Practical.
Good in the snow.
OK.
Are you hungry?
It's about a two hour drive,
but we can stop
for something if you want.
No, I'm OK.
I think you're gonna
like the cottage.
It's, uh, relaxing.
Ah, is that what
we are going to do?
Relax?
I hope so.
I would like to relax with you.
For once.
I bought groceries,
so we don't need to leave.
Or not leave much.
If we don't want to.
Thank you for inviting me.
I'm glad you're here.
Me too, but...
also, like, terrified, yeah?
Did anyone recognize you?
At the airport or anything?
No, no. Not that I noticed.
Cool.
The cottage is super private,
so we don't need to worry
about anything.
-Not even your parents?
-No.
I told them I was
on a silent retreat,
like a meditation thing.
What? Does that sound fake?
Yes!
Ah!
It would if it was
anyone but you.
I can carry my own bag.
How are your ribs?
Fine, I can take my bag.
I can't believe you played
with those bruised ribs.
Whoa, you can't?
OK, maybe I can.
Wow!
Your real estate fetish
really paid off, huh?
I didn't buy this.
I had it built.
Oh, I know.
I can give you a tour,
if you'd like,
or I could make us some lunch.
There's plenty of food.
Also, I bought you Cokes,
though the water here
is really good.
I have my own well.
You can see it.
In case you're thirsty.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Wait, um, it's been a while,
so I might not last long.
Yes, same,
but we have two weeks.
Yeah, cool.
W-wait, same?
Mmm.
You said "same."
You haven't been
with anyone lately?
No.
Not since...
No, not since, so can we...
Really?
Hollander, it's not
a big deal, OK?
Yeah, but it's been...
Months, yes, I know.
So can we fuck now, please?
I haven't either.
Not since the last time.
I have an idea.
What?
For the next two weeks,
let's just be honest
with each other...
about what we
actually think and...
maybe how we really feel?
I will try.
Really?
Yes.
I will do anything
if it will make you touch
my dick right now.
Should I show you to your room?
There's two
guest rooms downstairs,
so plenty to choose from.
Mmm. I will need
a king-size bed.
They all have a king-size bed.
And a view.
They all have a view.
Hmm. And I will need a...
What do you call it?
An en-suite bedroom.
Well, that might be a problem.
Oh, why is that?
There's only one
with an en-suite.
-And it's mine.
-Ah...
This is awkward.
This room isn't available
to the guests.
Mmm. Disappointing.
I'm sorry, sir. We'd really
like to accommodate you, but...
Sir, I'm just a bellboy!
You can't treat
the staff like this.
Oh, I think I know how the
staff likes to be treated
after all these years, hmm?
Wait.
Wait, wait, wait.
Uh, no.
Ah.
Why are you making
so many burgers?
The recipe was for eight, so...
OK, you cut it in half.
What, you can't do math?
Leave me alone.
No.
OK, fine. I should have
cut it in half.
Ordinarily, I would give
the rest to my parents,
but that would probably ruin
my whole silent retreat lie,
I guess.
Yuna and David, yes?
Mm-hmm.
And?
And what?
Tell me about them.
What do you want to know?
I don't know.
I don't know anything.
I know your mother
is Japanese or something.
Probably where you
get your looks.
Half of them, yeah.
And your dad is, what, boring?
Is that where you
get your boring from?
He's not boring.
So, he's exciting,
reading the New Yorker?
He's normal, OK?
He works for the
Treasury Board of Canada.
Hmm. Crazy!
Fuck you!
He played hockey for McGill.
Whoa. McGill?
What the fuck is McGill?
Is McGill a town?
It's a really good school.
My parents are great.
Do they know?
About you?
Of course not.
No, about you.
No.
Would they not be good about it?
I don't know.
I mean, no, they'd be fine.
I'm sure they would be, but...
I don't know.
We haven't talked about it.
Sometimes, I think I would have
told them already.
Oh, this is my fault.
No.
Well, I mean, yeah, kind of.
Look...
I think you can tell
your parents you're gay
without giving them a list
of all the guys you're fucking.
I know, I know.
Anyways, it just
doesn't really matter.
You done?
Nice, right?
So we just sit here
and look at it?
Yes.
We just sit here and look at it.
Canada is fun.
Shut up!
It was just Rose.
Mmm. Just Rose?
She's just checking in.
You're not jealous, are you?
No.
Ilya, I'm gay.
Yeah, not so gay you
can't fuck Rose Landry.
Oh my God.
It was, like, twice.
And both times
were complete disasters.
I'm not sure she's looking
for a repeat performance.
Oh, disasters like how?
I'm not going into details.
What the fuck was that?
A loon?
A what?
A loon. It's a bird.
Sounds like a fucking wolf.
It's a bird, trust me.
You're so scared.
What kind of a bird
makes a noise like that?
A loon! A fucking wolf?
Stupid Canadian wolf bird.
Oh, so now you speak bird, too.
Fluent.
I hate you.
No, you don't.
Have you talked to
your brother lately?
Mm-mmm.
Is that a good thing?
Probably, I don't know.
I'm sorry about your family.
Even if they suck,
you must miss them.
My mother didn't suck.
She was great.
How did she die?
By accident.
She accidentally swallowed
a whole bottle of pills.
How old were you?
12.
I found her.
I don't want you
to think she was weak.
I don't.
She wasn't.
She was so funny and beautiful.
She was so sad.
And my dad was so hard on her.
And...
Motherfucker!
Do you wanna go inside?
No.
Good morning.
I like you.
I like you too.
You can't pick Montreal.
Yes, I can.
I've always wondered what it
would be like to be a Metro.
You know, historically,
they're the best team in sport.
Better than the fucking Yankees.
Oh, I know so.
Well, I'm gonna be Boston.
Good choice.
I'm gonna fucking kill you.
I am you.
Well, you're not anything.
I'm on the cover
of the fucking game.
Oh, fuck. It's Hayden.
He just had a baby. I haven't
talked to him in weeks.
You're a baby.
Hey, buddy.
Yeah, uh, how's...
I know, I'm so sorry.
But how's Amber, right?
How is she?
Oh, yeah, the pics are cute.
Oh, good, good.
And Jacki's good too?
Is it better than, um...
Yeah, no, I... I remember that.
That was a tough time.
Uh, sorry, hey, just, um,
my mom's on the other line.
I'm just gonna get
rid of her, OK?
What are you doing?
I think you know.
Please stop.
I don't think
it's what you want.
Later, OK?
OK, I make you a deal.
I won't touch you,
but if you get hard...
I won't get hard.
OK, so no problem then.
Ilya...
Shane...
Uh, sorry, man, yeah,
my mom is so annoying sometimes.
Sorry, you were saying?
Oh, right, yeah, yeah, Mark.
And that's her middle brother?
Brother-in-law, right.
But he's the one...
Got it, right, yeah,
from Thanksgiving.
Yeah, yeah, he's... he's great.
Uh...
Well, that's nice
he could come and stay.
Cool, cool, yeah, yeah,
that makes sense.
Uh, no, nothing much here.
The headaches are better.
Fuck.
No, sorry, just a text.
Totally.
Yeah, it's totally clear,
so all's well there.
Ah, jeez.
Sorry, hey, one second.
Oh, fuck. Oh, fuck!
Ah. Sorry, man,
I just... I have to run.
Someone's at the door.
Fuck...
No, it's just...
It's just Amazon.
But, um, I'll call you
next week, and...
Yeah, yeah, so, totally.
And, uh...
All right, yes, love you, man.
And give my best
to Jacki and the kids.
Fuck you, fuck you.
Why was that so hot?
Because you like to be bad.
Hey, that's not what this is.
You and me.
Maybe it was at first,
but not now
and not for a long time.
So, you love Hayden?
All right...
So I was thinking I'm
a free agent next season.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
You wouldn't
re-sign with Boston?
Then where?
I don't know, I was thinking
maybe a Canadian team.
Not Montreal, huh?
No, I mean, I know.
But I would love to not
have Russian passport.
I could marry Svetlana.
She's American.
Would be easy citizenship.
She would do it.
Her father is goalie
Sergei Vitrov.
Yeah, you've told me.
She would help me.
But...
is she, I don't know,
someone you'd want to marry?
We are friends.
We would be fine.
And it would be
for the passport.
OK, but...
But what?
But you like women, right?
You could find someone
you'd want to marry for real
and still get the passport.
Maybe, but...
But what?
I have this problem.
What's the problem?
I like women, yes?
Yeah, I know.
And everywhere I go,
I'm surrounded
by beautiful women.
And they love me.
Sounds rough.
Yes, it is.
Listen.
And these women,
they're so sexy and fun.
But I am always thinking about
this slow fucking hockey player
with beautiful freckles.
And a weak backhand.
A weak backhand?
Yes, very weak.
And he's so boring,
and he drives this terrible car.
It's a normal car!
I am always wishing that
these women were him.
It's a terrible problem, huh?
Do you want that problem
to go away?
Mm-mmm.
I don't ever want that problem
to ever go away.
Don't marry Svetlana.
Just don't.
I know it wouldn't be
for love or whatever.
Just don't.
We can figure
something else out, OK?
OK.
Mmm.
I have another idea.
What idea? What is happening?
What if you played in Ottawa?
Ottawa is the same
division as Boston.
We're still rivals.
OK, but listen.
First off, super close by.
Second, Ottawa needs
a star center,
and they're nowhere near
their cap,
so they could definitely
afford you.
And maybe we could start to
change the narrative a bit.
What?
Hollander, I just woke up.
What is narrative?
Boston and Montreal.
That's intense.
Everyone knows that.
But Montreal and Ottawa?
And look, lots of guys have
friends on other teams.
We're not rookies anymore.
There are younger guys coming in
frothing at the mouth.
Let them hate each other.
We don't need to keep this up
until we retire, do we?
We're not fucking wrestlers.
Hollander, Hollander,
OK, it's very late.
And this is so many words.
What are you getting at?
You play for Ottawa.
I play for Montreal.
OK? We're only two hours apart,
and we start a charity.
Something that, you know,
we both care about.
And we come up with a story,
like I approached you.
Or I approached you.
Fine, sure.
And we tell
the press and everyone
that by working on this cause
that we both love,
that we developed a mutual
respect for one another and,
um...
And we like sucking
each other's dicks.
Any questions?
Fuck off.
This is a good idea, Rozanov.
OK, OK!
It's not bad.
So we start the charity.
Yeah, and it wouldn't
be bullshit either.
Like, we can really
start a charity.
Something cool that means
a lot to both of us.
And, you know,
we still play hard
against each other on the ice.
Shut up!
And then if people saw us
out in public or whatever,
it wouldn't be so fucking crazy.
And we're only two hours
apart all year round.
Apply for, like,
citizenship here in Canada.
And maybe one day
when we both retire...
we could be together.
For real.
You really think
that far ahead, Hollander?
I do.
About this.
And is that what you want?
To be together?
So much.
So much it scares me.
Hey...
I love you.
Holy shit.
I mean...
I love you too.
Fuck, Hollander.
Oh my God, I love you so much.
Does it...
Does it fucking kill you too?
Not anymore.
How did we let this happen?
We were both very stupid
and irresponsible.
This is real though, right?
Yeah.
Please fuck me.
What was your mother's name?
Irina.
Why?
I was thinking we could
start a hockey school.
Like a summer camp for kids.
And give the money away to
mental health organizations.
Like suicide prevention.
It was just an idea.
She would have loved you.
Like I love you.
Say it again in Russian, please.
Whoo!
Is this where you do yoga,
or up there?
No, I do it inside.
The producer wanted me...
Wait, you saw that?
Yeah, it was very good.
I needed help sleeping, so...
You're an asshole.
How's the water?
You're in it.
Yeah, but I want to know
how you like it.
Fuck you! What if my phone
was in my pocket?
Ah, it's not.
You left it on the table.
It's been ringing all morning.
You're still an asshole.
-Give me a kiss.
-You're cold.
Do you want pasta
from last night or hot dogs?
Hot dogs.
OK, they're gonna
have to defrost a bit.
So we have a little time.
Maybe. What do you
have in mind?
Nothing that'll take too long.
Ah...
Oh, fuck.
Maybe you should...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Do you want me to...
-No, no.
Fuck.
Fuck, this is
a fucking nightmare.
Shane...
Oh, fuck, this is
a fucking nightmare.
Oh, what the fuck
am I supposed to do?
Ah!
We should go talk to him.
Yeah, what if he doesn't
want to talk to me?
What if...
Fuck, my mom!
Hey, hey, hey,
they will talk to you.
Yeah, but I fucking
lied to them.
For so many years,
I fucking lied to them,
and now my dad
just walks in on me.
This...
This is my fucking nightmare.
This is my actual
fucking nightmare, Ilya!
OK, OK.
Then maybe it's time
to wake up, yes?
Fuck, I'm scared.
Yes, it's scary.
But you're brave.
Shut up.
You are, you're brave.
I feel like I'm gonna die.
So much for easing them into it.
Maybe... maybe he
didn't even notice.
Hmm?
OK, I'm gonna get changed.
I'm gonna drive over. Uh...
And then...
And then fuck!
What am I gonna say?
Oh!
Do you... do you want me
to come with you?
Would you?
Of course.
OK...
-OK.
That... that is not gonna help.
Oh, they don't know
I play for Boston?
Uh, maybe you should
wait in the car.
Fuck, never mind, sorry.
Hey, it's me, Shane.
Hi.
I left my charger at your place,
and it's the old one
that fits into my phone,
and all the other chargers
we have are newer, so...
It's OK, Dad.
I'm sorry. You shouldn't
have found out that way.
Found out what, exactly?
I'm gay.
Which I was gonna tell you soon.
I'm sorry I didn't
tell you sooner. I...
Yeah, and this is Ilya.
Rozanov.
But you already know that.
Hi.
He's visiting, and we're, uh...
-Lovers.
-No, Ilya, that's gross.
But you hate him.
No.
I mean, I get that,
but no, I actually, uh...
I love him.
I did not want this
to be how I told you.
Uh, I'm sorry.
Can we just sit down, please?
Here.
I think we thought
maybe you were gay.
You did?
I think we thought
it was certainly possible.
For how long?
Mmm, for a while, I guess.
We both know you
pretty well, Shane.
I mean, what we did not suspect
was that you were
so friendly with Rozanov.
-Ilya.
-Ilya, sorry.
I know.
It's a long story.
When did this happen?
Wait.
The All-Star game.
You two had so much chemistry.
No, it was before then.
Wow!
Wow. Wow.
So, when?
Since our, uh, rookie season.
Since your rookie season?
No, it's not true.
Since before that.
Not helpful.
Before?
The summer before.
So you've been in love since...
-No! No, no, no.
-No, no, no, no.
No, just...
Just what?
Uh, just...
Just...
-Ilya.
-Oh, OK.
Just what?
Lovers.
OK, no one is allowed
to use that word again.
Well, I would love a drink.
And there were no nice men
in Montreal?
I don't know.
Probably there were.
And do your teammates know?
No, nobody knows.
This is good vodka.
Thanks. I try to buy
the Russian stuff.
Mmm.
You never...
I mean, you never let him win,
did you, Shane?
Do you let Dad win at cards?
I'd rather die.
-Same here.
-OK.
So is your plan to, what,
just keep doing this in secret
until you both retire, or...
Probably. I don't know.
Probably, yes.
Oh, no, that's sad.
I know. We know.
We just can't come out
and, like, announce it.
Ilya, I gotta say,
I'm surprised.
You have such a reputation
as a ladies' man.
Mmm. It's not untrue.
Ilya likes both.
Oh.
It's true, I've been
with many women, but...
I have only been in love
with one person.
Same here.
Only one.
Well, just...
-Hey.
-Hi.
Thank you.
Mom, um...
I need you to know
that I did really try.
I tried really hard, but, um...
I just can't help it.
And I'm sorry.
Oh, no, you have nothing,
nothing to apologize for.
Look at me. Look at me.
Look at me.
I'm sorry that I made you feel
like you couldn't tell me.
Hey...
I am so, so proud of you.
OK?
Please forgive me.
I forgive you, Mom.
I love you.
Oh, I love you too.
So much.
You OK?
Yeah.
All right... OK.
OK. OK, OK, enough.
All right, what's the plan?
We need a statement prepared
in case anything leaks.
Something classy and simple.
Mom...
And I'm gonna quietly
reach out to the premium brands,
or maybe just Reebok
and Rolex and Speedo.
They'll be thrilled, I think,
once they wrap
their minds around this.
There's a world
of opportunity here,
if they do it right.
Mom, can you just take
three steps back, please?
I'm not gonna come out
or anything yet.
We just want...
a future.
I don't know.
You play in Ottawa?
Yes. We would be closer,
and with the charity.
Mmm, and you have no
loyalty to Boston?
Jesus, Mom!
What? They drafted him.
You would leave Boston
for Shane?
Yes.
-Hmm.
-Mom?
Loyalty is important.
He's trying to be loyal to me,
not Boston.
Well...
My mom cares a little
too much about hockey.
Now I see where you get it from.
Have you talked to Scott Hunter?
-No.
-I did.
You did?
Yeah, briefly.
After MLH award in June.
And what did he say?
Nothing.
I didn't tell him
about Shane and me.
But what he did, it was...
Yes, it was very brave.
It changed things
for me at least.
Maybe for us.
Shane...
Shane.
I'm OK.
I'm just freaking out.
I'll be OK in a second.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
We're good here.
Your family is here.
Your boyfriend is here.
You're good here, OK?
My boyfriend?
I mean, yes.
I think so, probably.
Since rookie season...
The summer before.
I'll bring the chicken
and some salad stuff.
Pick up beer in town.
Please text.
Why? We'll just
be there around 5:00.
-Please text.
-We'll text.
Pay attention to your phones.
-Thank you for pasta.
-Thank you!
Drive safely. I love you.
Love you!
♪ I said, saddle up, cowboy,
I'm waiting for you ♪
♪ Won't you give it up? ♪
♪ Don't be another one of 'em ♪
♪ Be one of us
Come on, come on, come on ♪
♪ We've got bad things to do ♪
♪ Baby, take me,
don't hesitate ♪
♪ With a girl like me,
you better activate ♪
♪ I'm a tidal wave
coming for your grave ♪
♪ I wanna do
bad things with you ♪
♪ Then your fireworks
set me off ♪
♪ I'm like a time bomb
in a storm ♪
♪ In your arms I'd start a war ♪
♪ We've both been here before ♪
♪ Matter of fact,
I caught you looking back ♪
♪ So let's go ♪
♪ I get what I want ♪
♪ I want what I see ♪
♪ I wanna do, do, do, do ♪
♪ Bad things with you ♪
♪ I mean, oh my God ♪
♪ Come on,
I know you feel it too ♪
♪ Like summer's on so hot ♪
♪ You put your record on ♪
♪ My panties drop,
and I don't wanna stop playing ♪
♪ It's on, babe ♪
♪ I know you're not shy ♪
♪ Baby, take me,
don't hesitate ♪
♪ With a girl like me
you better activate ♪
♪ I'm a tidal wave
coming for your grave ♪
♪ I wanna do
bad things with you ♪
♪ Then your fireworks
set me off ♪
♪ I'm like a time bomb
in a storm ♪
♪ In your arms I'd start a war ♪
♪ We've both been here before ♪
♪ Matter of fact,
I caught you looking back ♪
♪ So let's go ♪
♪ I get what I want ♪
♪ I want what I see ♪
♪ I wanna do, do, do, do ♪
♪ Bad things with you ♪
Closed Captions: MELS